Guide to the Cass Gilbert Papers and Architectural Drawings 1883-1952 (Bulk 1900-1934) PR 21
New-York Historical Society
- Series X. Architectural Drawings, 1883-1952
  - PR21.210: Montana Club
    - Folded drawings: full scale details (Offsite-box CG-20)
  - PR21.211: Montana State Capitol (Helena, Mont.), 1926
  - PR21.212: Montana State University (Bozeman, Mont.), 1917
  - PR21.213: Monument to the Preservation of Knowledge, 1933
    - Section and sketches. graphite on board, graphite on paper., 1934 January 12 (Object PR21.213.O1)
  - PR21.214: Howard Morris House (Milwaukee, Wis.)
  - PR21.215: Morris Park Railroad Station (Bronx, N.Y.)
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.216: W. S. Morton Casino (White Bear Lake, Minn.)
  - PR21.217: W. S. Morton, Manitou Island Cottage (White Bear Lake, Minn.)
  - PR21.218: O. W. Mosher House (New Richmond, Wis.), 1893
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-15)
  - PR21.219: Mount Vernon Civic Center (Mount Vernon, N.Y.)
  - PR21.220: Mount Vernon Shelter (New York, N.Y.)
    - Perspective study. colored pencil on board. (Object PR21.220.O1)
    - Two perspective studies. colored pencil on board. (Object PR21.220.O2)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-15)
  - PR21.221: Murray School (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.222: Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Building (Newark, N.J.), 1904
  - PR21.223: National Academy of Design (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.224: National Hall of Fame (Washington, D.C.), 1928-1933
    - Ground floor plan. graphite. presentation. (Object PR21.224.O1)
  - PR21.225: National Newark Banking Company (Newark, N.J.), 1904
  - PR21.226: National State Bank Building (Newark, N.J.), 1910-1915
    - Broad Street elevation. ink wash and graphite on board. (Object PR21.226.O1)
    - Perspective study. watercolor and graphite on paper and board. (Object PR21.226.O2)
    - Perspective study. watercolor and graphite on board., 1910 (Object PR21.226.O3)
    - Perspective study. ink on board., 1911 (Object PR21.226.O4)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-21)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-22)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-23)
  - PR21.227: John S. M. Neill, Residence Alterations (Helena, Mont.), 1908
  - PR21.228: New Castle County Wilmington Public Building (Wilmington, Pa.)
  - PR21.229: New Haven City Improvement Plan (New Haven, Conn.)
    - Two area plans. ink. presentation (Object PR21.229.O1)
    - Sketches 6 and 7 (area plans). ink on paper and board., 1908 January 25-26 (Object PR21.229.O2)
  - PR21.230: New Haven Courthouse (New Haven, Conn.)
    - Main floor plan. graphite. Front elevation. presentation. color., 1909 January (Object PR21.230.O1)
    - Preliminary sketch, second floor plan. graphite and ink on trace and board., 1909 January 22 (Object PR21.230.O2)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-24)
  - PR21.231: New Haven Hotel (New Haven, Conn.)
    - Two studies: plan of approaches and front elevation. graphite and watercolor on trace and board., 1908 February 21 (Object PR21.231.O1)
    - Two studies: ground and upper floor plans. graphite on trace and board., 1908 February 21 (Object PR21.231.O2)
  - PR21.232: New Haven Railroad Station (New Haven, Conn.)
    - Exterior perspective. graphite, charcoal, and watercolor on board. (Object PR21.232.O1)
    - Exterior perspective. graphite, colored pencil, and watercolor on board. (Object PR21.232.O2)
    - Exterior perspective. graphite, charcoal, and watercolor on board., 1911 July (Object PR21.232.O3)
    - Two elevation studies. graphite and watercolor on paper and board., 1916 November 1 (Object PR21.232.O4)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-24)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-25)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-26)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-27)
  - PR21.233: New Street Office Building (New York, N.Y.), 1911
  - PR21.234: New York Athletic Club (Travers Island, N.Y.)
  - PR21.235: New York City Club (New York, N.Y.), 1900
  - PR21.236: New York City Post Office (New York, N.Y.), 1908
    - Elevation study. graphite on paper and board (Object PR21.236.O1)
    - Two elevation studies. graphite and ink wash on paper and board. (Object PR21.236.O2)
    - Elevation studies on recto and verso. graphite on trace and board. (Object PR21.236.O3)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-38)
  - PR21.237: New York County Lawyer's Association Clubhouse (New York, N.Y.)
    - Auditorium (perspective study). crayon on paper and board., 1928 January 26 (Object PR21.237.O1)
    - Conference room [?] (perspective study). crayon on paper and board., 1928 (Object PR21.237.O2)
    - Main entrance (perspective study). crayon on paper and board., 1928 (Object PR21.237.O3)
    - Main floor lounge (perspective study). crayon on paper and board., 1928 (Object PR21.237.O4)
    - Front elevation study. graphite on paper and board. (Object PR21.237.O5)
    - Front elevation study. graphite and ink wash on board., 1928 January 26 (Item PR21.237.O6)
  - PR21.238: New York Life Insurance Company Building (New York, N.Y.), 1928
    - Exterior perspective "tower sketches". colored pencil on trace and board, 1922 (Object PR21.238.O1)
    - Exterior perspective. Graphite on trace and board., 1923 November (Object PR21.238.O2)
    - Exterior perspective. Graphite on trace and board (Object PR21.238.O3)
    - Exterior perspective. Colored pencil on trace and board, 1922 (Object PR21.238.O4)
    - Exterior perspective. Colored pencil on trace and board (Object PR21.238.O5)
    - Exterior perspective. Colored pencil on trace and board (Object PR21.238.O6)
    - Exterior perspective. Colored pencil on trace and board, 1922 (Object PR21.238.O7)
    - Exterior perspective. Colored pencil on trace and board., 1922 (Object PR21.238.O8)
    - Exterior perspective. Colored pencil on trace and board., 1922 (Object PR21.238.O9)
    - Lobby looking toward main corridor. charcoal on trace and board., 1922 (Object PR21.238.O10)
    - Lobby looking toward main corridor, alternate. charcoal on trace and board., 1922 (Object PR21.238.O11)
    - Exterior perspective. colored pencil on trace and board., 1922 December 7 (Object PR21.238.O12)
    - Front elevation. graphite and ink wash on board. (Object PR21.238.O13)
    - Exterior perspective. graphite and colored pencil on board., 1924 November 6 (Object PR21.238.O14)
    - R.D.7 [perspective study]. charcoal on trace and board., 1926 June 16 (Object PR21.238.O15)
    - Exterior perspective. graphite and watercolor on board. (Object PR21.238.O16)
    - Two exterior perspectives, early designs. mixed media on board., 1923 (Object PR21.238.O17)
    - View of building from across Madison Square Park. collage (technique), mixed media on board. (Object PR21.238.O18)
    - Sketch of inside vestibule and sketch of avenue vestibules from outside. crayon on trace and board., 1926 August 6 (Object PR21.238.O19)
    - Lobby looking toward main corridor (perspective study). crayon on trace and board. (Object PR21.238.O20)
    - Exterior perspective "R.D.5". graphite and crayon on board., 1926 May 3 (Object PR21.238.O21)
    - Perspective study of design "YB". graphite and crayon on board., 1925 May 5 (Object PR21.238.O22)
    - End elevation "Y-B". mixed media on board., 1925 May 5 (Object PR21.238.O23)
    - Exterior perspective study. colored pencil on trace and board., 1924 October (Object PR21.238.O24)
    - Exterior perspective study "RD5A". crayon on board. (Object PR21.238.O25)
    - Exterior perspective study "RD6". graphite on board., 1926 May 8 (Object PR21.238.O26)
    - Exterior perspective study "RD4A". charcoal on trace and board., 1926 April 27 (Object PR21.238.O27)
    - Interior elevation study. graphite, charcoal, and watercolor on paper. (Object PR21.238.O28)
    - Exterior perspective study. ink and watercolor on linen., 1923 October (Object PR21.238.O29)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-28)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-29)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-30)
    - Folded drawings: plumbing, electric, heating, sewage (Offsite-box CG-31)
    - Folded drawings: 13-20 (Offsite-box CG-32)
    - Folded drawings: 1-12 (Offsite-box CG-33)
    - Folded drawings: 28, 29, 30, 32 (Offsite-box CG-34)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-35)
    - Folded drawings: 22-27 (Offsite-box CG-36)
    - Folded drawings: 33-34B (Offsite-box CG-37)
  - PR21.239: New York Life Townhouse
    - Exterior perspective. ink on board. (Object PR21.239.O1)
  - PR21.240: New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad, Westchester Avenue Station
  - PR21.241: New York University (New York, N.Y.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-39)
  - PR21.242: Newark Memorial (Newark, N.J)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-38)
  - PR21.242A: Newark Office Building (Newark, NJ), 1909
    - Sketch, Broad Street elevation. graphite and ink wash on trace and board., 1909 December (Object PR21.242A.O1)
  - PR21.243: Newtown Creek Project (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.244: N.H.F.H. Railroad, Grade Station (New York), 1907
    - Elevation study. graphite and watercolor on trace and board., 1907 April 30 (Object PR21.244.O1)
  - PR21.245: Norris Building (Boston, Mass.), 1894
  - PR21.246: Northern Pacific and Manitoba Railroad, Hotel and Office (Winnipeg, Man.), 1899
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-40)
  - PR21.247: Northern Pacific Railroad, Bridge over Lexington Avenue (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.248: Northern Pacific Railroad Comapny Clubhouse, 1896
  - PR21.249: Northern Pacific Railroad Depot (Bismark, N.D.)
  - PR21.250: Northern Pacific Railroad Depot (Little Falls, Minn.), 1899
  - PR21.251: Northern Pacific Railroad Depot (Fargo, N.D.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-40)
  - PR21.252: Northern Pacific Railroad Office, 1918
  - PR21.253: Northern Pacific Railroad, Office and Station (Portland, Or.), 1893
    - Exterior perspective. watercolor on board. (Object PR21.253.O1)
    - Conference room (perspective study). watercolor and graphite on trace and board. (Object PR21.253.O2)
      see PR21.366.O18
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-48)
  - PR21.254: Northern Pacific Railroad Office, 4th Street Building (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1896-1897
    - Exterior perspective. watercolor on board. (Object PR21.254.O1)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-40)
  - PR21.255: Northern Pacific Railroad Depot and Train Shed (Seattle, Wa.)
  - PR21.256: Northern Pacific Railroad Station (Yakima, Wa.)
  - PR21.257: Northwestern National Bank (Minneapolis, Minn.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-41)
  - PR21.258: Northwestern Life Insurance Company (Milwaukee, Wis.)
    - Scheme "N" [perspective study]. graphite and watercolor on board., 1910 August 29 (Object PR21.258.O1)
  - PR21.259: C. P. Noyes House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-38)
  - PR21.260: C. P. Noyes, Manitou Island Lodge (White Bear Lake, Minn.)
    - Perspective study. ink on board. (Object PR21.260.O1)
  - PR21.261: Oberlin College (Oberlin, Ohio), 1905-1925
    - General plan. ink on board, 1905 (Object PR21.261.O1)
    - Theological School quadrangle. watercolor on board., 1930 May 13 (Object PR21.261.O2)
    - Campus plan, scheme B. ink on board. (Object PR21.261.O3)
    - Preliminary study for Art Building, A. graphite on board. (Object PR21.261.O4)
    - Preliminary sketch for Art Building, B (Object PR21.261.O5)
    - Administration group perspective study. colored pencil on board. (Object PR21.261.O6)
    - Administration Building, perspective study. watercolor and colored pencil on trace and board., 1912 July 22 (Object PR21.261.O7)
    - Rough sketch showing proposed location for Administration Building in relation to Memorial Arch. ink on board (Object PR21.261.O8A)
    - Sketch for cloister to connect Finney Chapel with Administration Building. graphite on trace and board., 1914 October 9 (Object PR21.261.O8B)
    - Folded drawings: class and chapel building, dormitories, theological building (Offsite-box CG-42)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-43)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-44)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-45)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-46)
    - Folded drawings: athletic field, chapel (Offsite-box CG-47)
  - PR21.262: 42nd Street and Madison Avenue Office Building (New York, N.Y.), 1912
    - Exterior perspective. graphite and watercolor on board., 1912 (Object PR21.262.O1)
    - Exterior perspective. graphite on trace and board., 1919 November 16 (Object PR21.262.O2)
  - PR21.262A: Office Building and Warehouse Project, 1906-1908
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.263: Lucius F. Ordway House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-48)
  - PR21.264: Paris Hospital (Paris, France)
  - PR21.265: Pasadena Casino (Pasadena, Calif.), 1910
  - PR21.265A: Peace Monument (New York, N.Y.), 1918
    - Elevation study from river (Frederick Ruckstull?). graphite and crayon on board., 1918 November (Object PR21.265A.O1)
    - Elevation study from river (Frederick Ruckstull?). graphite, ink wash, and crayon on board., 1918 November (Object PR21.265A.O2)
  - PR21.266: Pelham Manor Station
  - PR21.267: Pennsylvania Power and Light Building Competition (Allentown, Pa.)
  - PR21.268: Philadelphia Office Building (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1920
  - PR21.269: Pietro Monument (France), 1917
    - Perspective study. graphite and ink on board., 1917 August 29 (Object PR21.269.O1)
    - Sketch plan. graphite and watercolor on board., 1917 August (Object PR21.269.O2)
  - PR21.270: Pomeroy Building (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Store building on the "Pomroy Property" [front elevation study]. ink on paper. (Object PR21.270.O1)
  - PR21.271: Post House
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-48)
  - PR21.272: Presbyterian Church (Chicago, Ill.)
  - PR21.273: Protestant Orphan Asylum (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.274: Prudential Insurance Company of America Building [Gibralter Building] (Newark, N.J.), 1927
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-50)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-51)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-52)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-53)
    - Folded drawings: Broad & Academy building (Offsite-box CG-54)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-55)
    - Folded drawings: misc. blueprints (Offsite-box CG-56)
    - Folded drawings: 1-10 (Offsite-box CG-57)
    - Folded drawings: 11-16 (Offsite-box CG-58)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-59)
    - Folded drawings: blueprints (Offsite-box CG-60)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-61)
  - PR21.275: Railroad Station (Old Lyme, Conn.), 1907
  - PR21.276: Como Park Railroad Viaduct (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.277: Rantone Building
  - PR21.278: Realty Company of Boston, Building Alteration (Great Falls, Mont.), 1902
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-63)
  - PR21.279: Realty Company of Boston Warehouse (Minneapolis, Minn.), 1901
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-62)
  - PR21.280: Regina Legislative and Executive Building (Regina, Sask.)
  - PR21.281: Remington Arms, Union Metallic Cartridge Armory (Bridgeport, Conn.), 1914
  - PR21.282: Charles Rich House
  - PR21.283: Richardson Memorial Library, Saint Louis Art Museum (St. Louis, Mo.)
    - Sketch of rooms number six and number seven. Graphite on trace and board., 1912 October 21 (Object PR21.283.O1)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-69)
  - PR21.284: Ridgefield House (Ridgefield, Conn.)
    - Exterior perspective study. graphite [?] on paper., 1916 May 20 (Object PR21.284.O1)
  - PR21.285: Ridgefield School (Ridgefield, Conn.), 1909
  - PR21.286: Ridgefield Town Hall (Ridgefield, Conn.)
  - PR21.287: C. E. Riggs House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Study for house. watercolor and ink on brittle board. (Object PR21.287.O1)
  - PR21.288: Riverside Drive, 1928
    see also: George Washington Bridge
    - Scheme "C" [perspective study]. graphite on paper with matting, 1928 (Object PR21.288.O1)
    - Scheme "A" [perspective study]. graphite on paper with matting., 1928 (Object PR21.288.O2)
    - Scheme "A" [bird's-eye view]. graphite on paper with matting., 1928 (Object PR21.288.O3)
    - Scheme "C" [perspective study]. graphite on paper with matting., 1928 (Object PR21.288.O4)
    - Scheme "C" [bird's eye view]. graphite on paper with matting., 1928 (Object PR21.288.O5)
    - Scheme "A" [perspective study]. graphite on paper and board (damaged)., 1928 (Object PR21.288.O6)
  - PR21.289: Rockefeller Plaza (New York, N.Y.)
    - Folded drawings: studies (Offsite-box CG-63)
  - PR21.290: Rodin Studios (New York, N.Y.), 1918
  - PR21.291: Roosevelt Field Airport (Long Island, N.Y.)
    - A study for administration and terminal building. colored pencil on board., 1929 April 5 (Object PR21.291.O1)
    - Study for hotel. watercolor, colored pencil, and graphite on board., 1929 April 5 (Object PR21.291.O2)
  - PR21.292: Roselawn Cemetary
  - PR21.293: Rowe, Judge D. Watson, House (Chambersburg, Pa.), 1882
  - PR21.294: Rowe Memorial, 1887
  - PR21.295: Sailor's Snug Harbor, Apartment Building for Trustees (Staten Island, New York, N.Y.), 1920
    - Exterior perspective study. graphite and crayon on board., 1922 March 7 (Object PR21.295.O1)
      Housed with PR21.361.O7
  - PR21.296: Saint Clement's Church (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.297: Saint Clement's Memorial Church (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.298: Saint Clement's Opera House (Sioux Falls, S.D.), 1894
  - PR21.299: Saint John's Church (Moorehead, Minn.)
  - PR21.300: Saint John's Church (Waterbury, Conn.), 1916-1917
  - PR21.301: Saint John the Evangelist Church (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1895
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-67)
  - PR21.302: Saint Louis County Courthouse (Saint Louis, Mo.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-78)
  - PR21.303: Saint Louis National Bank and Trust Company (Saint Louis, Mo.), 1919
    See also: First National Bank, St. Louis
    - Front elevation study. graphite and ink wash on paper and board., 1919 June 9 (Object PR21.303.O1)
    - Perspective study. graphite and ink wash on board., 1919 (Object PR21.303.O2)
    - Perspective study. colored pencil and watercolor on board., 1919 May (Object PR21.303.O3)
    - Perspective study. graphite and colored pencil on trace and board., 1919 June 12 (Object PR21.303.O4)
    - Perspective study. graphite and watercolor on board. (Object PR21.303.O5)
  - PR21.304: Saint Louis Public Library (Saint Louis, Mo.), 1908
    - Central Building, ground floor plan. ink on linen and board. (Object PR21.304.O1)
    - Central Building, main floor plan. ink on linen and board. (Object PR21.304.O2)
    - Central Building, second floor plan. ink on linen and board. (Object PR21.304.O3)
    - Olive Street elevation. graphite and ink on board (Object PR21.304.O4)
    - Interior elevation sketch. graphite on trace and board. (Object PR21.304.O5)
    - Central Building, main floor plan. mixed media on board. (Object PR21.304.O6)
    - Interior perspective. graphite on board. (Object PR21.304.O7)
    - Bird's eye view. graphite on paper. (Object PR21.304.O8)
    - Sketch of floor plan "Mr. Gilbert". charcoal on trace paper, hinged to board. (Object PR21.304.O9)
    - Front elevation study. graphite and crayon on trace, hinged to board. (Object PR21.304.O10)
    - Study for sunken garden [area plan]. watercolor and ink on paper removed from board. (Object PR21.304.O11)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-70)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-71)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-72)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-73)
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-74)
    - Rolled and folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-75)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-76)
  - PR21.305: Saint Martin's by the Lake Episcopal Church (Minnetonka, Minn.), 1888
  - PR21.306: Saint Mary's Seminary (Baltimore, Md.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-90)
  - PR21.307: Saint Paul Capitol Approaches, Improvement of Summit Avenue (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1909
    - Rolled and folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-91)
  - PR21.308: Saint Paul Public Library (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1901
  - PR21.309: Saint Paul Storefronts (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1888
    - Study for a store building. ink on paper., 1883 (Object PR21.309.O1)
  - PR21.310: Saint Paul's Episcopal Church (Virginia, Minn.), 1895
  - PR21.311: Saint Paul's Theological Seminary (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-77)
  - PR21.312: Saint Peter's Hospital, Brewer Building (Helena, Mont.), 1908
    - Exterior perspective. watercolor on board. (Object PR21.312.O1)
  - PR21.313: A. L. Schepp Building, 1913
  - PR21.314: Scheuer Building (Newark, N.J.), 1906
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-77)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-81)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-82)
  - PR21.315: School of Industrial Arts (Trenton, N.J.), 1909
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-83)
  - PR21.316: T. L. Schurmier House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1883
  - PR21.317: Schurmier Warehouse (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1892
    - Study for entrance. charcoal on board. (Object PR21.317.O1)
  - PR21.318: James Scott Memorial Fountain (Detroit, Mich.), 1911-1925
    - Elevation. graphite and ink wash on board., 1911 November 3 (Object PR21.318.O1)
    - Elevation. graphite and ink wash on board. (Object PR21.318.O2)
    - Study. ink and graphite on board., 1919 September 3 (Object PR21.318.O3)
    - Folded drawing (Offsite-box CG-90)
  - PR21.319: Scoville Manufacturing Company (Waterbury, Conn.), 1917
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-84)
  - PR21.320: Seabury Divinity School College (Faribault, Minn.), 1892
  - PR21.321: Searle Store Building (Saint Paul, Minn.)
    - Rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-194)
  - PR21.322: Seaside Sanatorium (Waterford, Conn.), 1934
    - "The Seaside Hospital" exterior perspective. graphite on trace and board. (Object PR21.322.O1)
    - Proposed plot plan showing possible development. graphite and ink wash on board. (Object PR21.322.O2)
    - Folded drawings: employees' home (Offsite-box CG-78)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-79)
  - PR21.323: Second Battery National Guard State of New York Armory (New York, N.Y.)
  - PR21.324: C. A. Severance, Summit Avenue Residence (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.324A: William Seward Monument (Seattle, Wash.), 1908
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-85)
  - PR21.324B: Shakespeare Garden [?] sun-dial (Stratford-upon-Avon, England)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-90)
  - PR21.325: Shattuck School (Faribault, Minn.), 1894
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-85)
    - Folded and rolled drawings (Offsite-box CG-86)
  - PR21.326: Hon. D. Shell Residence (Worthing, Minn.), 1899
  - PR21.327: Sioux Falls Opera House (Sioux Falls, S.D.)
    - Sketch for an opera house [exterior perspective]. watercolor and graphite on paper and board., 1894 February 27 (Object PR21.327.O1)
  - PR21.328: Sixth and Minnesota Bank Building (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1895
  - PR21.329: Mrs. Skinner House (Newport, R.I.) - McKim, Mead, and White, [1894]
    - Exterior study. watercolor and graphite on trace and board. (Object PR21.329/354.O1)
  - PR21.329A: J.H. Skinner House (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1894
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-85)
  - PR21.330: C. F. Smith House (Saint Paul, Minn.)
  - PR21.331: Social Center and Lodging House (Waterbury, Conn.), 1916
  - PR21.332: Soldiers Sailors and Marines Memorial (Duluth, Minn.), 1919
    - Elevation study. watercolor on paper (damaged). (Object PR21.332.O1)
    - Two drawings: Sketch (block plan and elevation), and detail study of monument. graphite, crayon, and watercolor on board., 1916 June 8 (Object PR21.332.O2)
    - Sketch (monument elevation). graphite, crayon, and watercolor on board., 1916 June 15 (Object PR21.332.O3)
    - Folded drawings (Offsite-box CG-90)
  - PR21.332A: Soldiers Sailors and Marines Memorial (Detroit, Mich.)
    - Design [front elevation study]. ink wash and graphite on paper and board., 1921 June 8 (Object PR21.332A.O1)